地の底の底の底
In the deep depths of the abyss!
強制労働施設で開かれた
地下チンチロ
Taking place in a slave labor facility, underground chinchiro!
初めて親を受けたカイジを
潰しにかかる
The foreman Ohtsuki and his underling Isawa
班長 大槻と 腹心 石和
seek to bankrupt Kaiji on his first deal!
張りは それぞれ２万
Each bets 20,000!
カイジ 大勝負！
Kaiji faces a fearsome foe!
石和　シゴロ 倍づけ
Isawa rolls 4-5-6, which pays double!
大槻　ゾロ目 ３倍づけ
And Ohtsuki rolls triples, which pay triple!
へたり込むカイジ
Kaiji sinks through the floor into debt hell!
借金地獄突入
25日が過ぎた
Twenty five days pass!
はーい 皆の衆
Okay, gentlemen!
お待ちかねの給料日です
It's finally payday!
１ヵ月の勤労 ご苦労さま
Thanks for your hard work this month!
はい
Here.
月に１度 この先の見えぬ
地下生活に訪れる
Once a month, a brief glimpse of hope is offered to those trapped in this abyss.
ささやかな癒やし
Here.
だがカイジにとっては
思い知らされる日
But for Kaiji, this day instead offers him a lesson.
現在 自分が置かれた境遇を
It informs him of his folly!
はーい それでは
お待たせしました
Oh, and sorry to keep you waiting.
４５組の皆さーん
It's time for the 45s!
カイジを含めた この６人の男たち
Six men, including Kaiji.
はい 北川さん　お疲れさま
Here, Kitagawa. Good work this month.
受け取る給料は２ヵ月先の前借り
The pay he receives now is an advance on two months hence!
そこから班長の手数料を
引かれた金額
From it is removed the foreman's share!
つまり正規の金額９万1000の
半分以下
Thus, it is less than half his true salary!
４万5000ペリカ
Only 45,000 perica!
いずれもカイジと同じ
博打で借金地獄に落ち
These men, like Kaiji, have been condemned by their gambling losses to debt hell!
４万5000しか受け取れぬ男たち
カイジを含めたこの６人は
侮蔑を込めて こう呼ばれていた
These six are mocked as such:
４５組！
The 45s!
お疲れさま カイジ君
Good work, Kaiji.
あれ？どうしたのかな
Problem?
君も前借りが必要だろう？
You need an advance, don't you?
クソッ この給料を叩き返し
Dammit...
If I hand this right back and don't take next month's pay...
来月の給料をもらわなければ
借金はチャラ
I'm out of the hole.
２ヵ月 耐えれば… 耐えれば…
If I can just hold on for two months...
はい！ビール冷えてるよ
Cold beer, right here!
5000ペリカ 5000ペリカ
Only 5,000 perica!
キンキンに冷えてるよ！
It's ice-cold!
２ヵ月 耐え忍ぶ
To endure two months!
今のカイジに
そんな気力は残っていない
Kaiji no longer has such willpower!
もう届かない
It is unreachable!
遠のいてしまった希望
His hopes recede!
１日外出券！
His hopes of the one-day furlough!
別にいいさ
もともと無理だったんだ
It doesn't matter anyway.
I never could've saved up half a million anyway.
50万ためるなんて
大体 あの外出券には
ただし書きがある
Plus, there's a catch to the furlough anyway.
組織が適正と判断した場合に限る
Only those approved by management are permitted a furlough!
入って間もない俺を
上があっさり認めるわけがねえ
I just got here. They'd never let me back out so soon.
どうせ無理
It's no good.
それに外に出れたって
Even if I make it out, I'd never be able to bay back ten million in a day.
1000万なんて金
１日でなんとかなるわけがねえ
己の心の弱さ 現実から目を背け
言い聞かせる
Kaiji, hiding from the truth of his weakness, makes excuses!
もともと絵空事
あり得ない夢　幻
It was always nothing but an impossible dream!
A phantasm!
決して かなわぬ幻
An unattainable phantasm!
結局 俺は働くしかねえんだ
I've just gotta keep working.
この地獄で15年
Fifteen years in this hell...
クソッ… あ？
Shit!
どうした？おい
What's wrong!?
Hey, are you okay!?
大丈夫か？
どうした？
What's going on?
ダメだ こりゃ
前田　病棟へ運んでやれ
Merde.
Maeda! Take him to the clinic!
はい 分かりました
カイジ君　手伝ってくれ
Okay.
Give me a hand, Kaiji.
え？ああ…
大丈夫だ…
I'm fine!
大丈夫だよ
Wait! I'm fine!
働ける…
I can work!
まだ働ける！
I can still work!
初めてだ　こっちのエリアは
This is the first time I've been in this area.
やだ… あそこは
No!
Not there!
頼む！あそこは いやだ！
Please! Anywhere but there!
まだ働ける　まだ働ける…
I can still work!
I can still...
先生　急患です
Doc! Another emergency!
そこに広がるのは地獄の中の地獄
What lay before him was a hell within a hell!
行き止まりの光景
The end of the line!
粉塵に肺をやられ
体を壊した者たち
Men whose strenuous labor had destroyed their bodies!
負け組の末路！
Those abandoned to their fate!
先生
Doc!
ああ その辺に置いといて
Yeah, sure, leave 'im over there.
あとで寝床 作っておくから
あ はい
I'll find him a mat later.
Okay...
なんか まともな治療
受けてるようには
It doesn't seem like they're going to take very good care of him.
見えなかったけど
薬は高いからな
Meds are expensive.
高いって… 金が要るのか？
当たり前だ
Expensive!?
You have to pay?
Of course.
持ってるわけないだろ
体を壊しちまったら 金なんて
But there's no way he can afford it!
If he's that beat up, he could never earn enough...
だから７～８割 戻らない
え？
That's why about three quarters of the men who go there never come back.
一度 体を壊したら
おしまいなんだよ
Once you break down...
It's the end for men like us.
俺たちは
冗談じゃねえ… 冗談じゃねえ
That's bullshit!
That's total bullshit!
冗談じゃねえ
That's complete and total bullshit!
耐えてみせる
I'll endure.
50万をためるまで
Until I've got my half-million.
欲望を断ち切って 外へ出るんだ
I'll hold back my desires, and make it out of here.
だが わずか１週間で揺らぐ決意
But in only a week, his resolve crumbles!
代わりに頭をもたげてくる
発散の欲望
Instead, his mind is filled with desire!
快楽の考思
And during recreation!
クソッ もうなんでもいい！
Dammit! I don't care anymore!
ダイブしたい　欲望の海に！
He wants to dive into a sea of desire!
崩れ落ちたい…
I want to collapse!
Abandon himself to utter destruction!
身を委ねたい　破滅に！
頑張りましょう
ここで使っちゃダメだ
Keep trying! You can't spend it here!
あと数時間でしょ
Remember, there's only a few more hours!
あと数時間？
A few days?
俺もカイジさんと同じ気持ちです
I feel the same way as you!
なんのことだ？
What are you talking about?
悲願は１日外出券　ですよね？
All we want is the one-day furlough!
Am I right?
ああ　まあな
I guess.
それを今夜 大勝ちして
ゲットしようっていうんでしょ？
So if we win big tonight, we'll be able to get our hands on it!
大勝ち？
Win big?
At chinchiro!
チンチロですよ
は？
この三好という男
This man, Miyoshi, heedless of Kaiji's failure,
あのカイジの ありさまを
見ていたにもかかわらず
初日 自分が勝ったことで
気をよくして
was emboldened by his first night's success
その後も毎回 賭場に参加
and participated in every session thereafter!
気がつけば 前借り生活
Before he realized it, he too was reduced to living on advances!
カイジと同じ ４５組に落ちたクチ
A 45, just like Kaiji!
今夜こそ 俺
いけると思うんです 絶対に
I really think I can win tonight!
I know it!
救えない男
You're hopeless.
気が弱いくせに
博打好きで お調子者
You don't have the nerves of steel a gambler needs. You just get carried away.
たまに勝つと有頂天になって
すぐに転落
You love it when you finally win, but then the tables turn.
100パーセント
人生を失敗するタイプだ
You're the kind of guy who's guaranteed to be a failure at life.
頑張りましょう カイジさん
Let's do our best, Kaiji!
俺は博打なんてしない
え？
No more gambling.
地道に50万ためる
何 言ってるんすか！
I'll earn my 500,000 honestly.
Seriously!?
前借りしてる俺たちが
50万ためようと思ったら
Counting our advances, that'll take a whole eight months!
８ヵ月ですよ　８ヵ月！
俺たちには無理です
It's impossible for us!
なぜなら意思が弱いから
We're too weak-willed!
カイジさん 今 もう
崩れそうだったじゃないですか
You were just about to give up, weren't you!?
まだ１週間なのに
With only a week left!
俺たちが外出券を手にするには
博打で勝つしかないんです
Gambling's the only way we'll ever earn enough for the furlough!
だから特別に
いいこと教えてあげます
Plus, I'll let you in on something!
出目にも いくつか
傾向があるんです
There are patterns in how the dice come up!
三好は自分が参加した賭場
すべての出目を克明にメモ
Miyoshi took detailed notes on each of the dice rolls in his games!
そのデータを検討
勝ちの傾向を探っていた
And within that data, he found a pattern to the winning rolls!
だが結果は大敗 連敗
But when attempting to use it, he failed! He lost every time!
ってことは結局 出目のデータも
無意味ってことじゃねえか
So doesn't that just mean the data's useless?
ほら ここを見ると分かります
Wait, look at this.
この｢ハ｣っていうのが
班長なんですけど
This "F" mark is for the foreman.
いや 班長の目はいつも強くって
He always rolls well.
それでも穴が まったくないって
わけじゃないんですけどね
But not perfectly, you know?
ほら こことか
Look at this.
ここなんかも…
And over here--
Hey, what are you doing!?
何するんですか！
偶然か？
Is this just a coincidence?
大槻がいい目を出す時は必ず
Every time Ohtsuki rolls really well...
両隣に石和と沼川がいる
He's between Isawa and Numakawa...
俺が負けたあの晩も同じだった
It was the same way when I lost!
待てよ！
Wait!
カイジの脳裏を貫く疑念
A thought pierces Kaiji's mind!
サイコロってのは立方体だから
Dice are cubic!
こう見えても こう見えても…
まさか！
So matter which way you look at them...
Is that it!?
疑念が確信に変わる！
This thought grows into conviction!
偶然なんかじゃねえ
This is no coincidence!
許せねえ！
I'll get him for this!
クソッ
Dammit!
カイジさん
Kaiji?
あの野郎…
That asshole!
あの野郎！
That fucking asshole!
許せねえ
I'll fucking get him!
許してたまるか！
He'll pay!
そりゃ傑作だ
It works great, doesn't it?
殴ってどうなる…
But if I smack him...
殴りつけて 怒鳴り散らして
そんなんじゃ…
If I smack him and start yelling...
Then...
何も変わらない
It won't change anything!
変わらないんだよ
Nothing will change!
All right!
第１土曜日 大槻班
On the first Saturday of the month, Ohtsuki sets up!
大盆 開帳！
Aww man...
仮に あの野郎の仕掛けが
俺の読みどおりだったとして
If his trick is what I think it is...
現場を押さえたとしても
Even if I stand up right now and try to press him on it...
｢初めてだ　出来心だ｣とか言って
He'll say he's never done it before.
せいぜい その勝負を
倍払いで済ます
And at best he'll just pay double.
そんな世間ずれした
ぬらりとした やり口で
I can't settle for just that!
くぐり抜けられてたまるか
もっと致命的 壊滅的な打撃を！
I need to hit him harder! Wipe him out!
どうしたらいい？
What do I do?
どうしたら…
What do I do!?
Kaiji's thoughts meander...
めまぐるしく回る思考
そして 見える
And then!
He sees!
突破口！その糸口！
An opening!
That hint!
いける！これなら倒せる
I can do it!
I can beat Ohtsuki with this!
大槻を！
だが奴を完全にぶっ潰すには
But I can't completely wipe him out by myself.
一人じゃ無理
数だ　頭数が必要だ
Numbers! I need strength in numbers!
カイジが近づいたのは
４５組の男たち
Kaiji notices the 45s!
今宵も勝負に敗れ
スカンピン どん底の負け組
Perpetual penniless losers!
つくづく お前らって負け組だよな
You guys are total losers.
あ？
鏡を見てみるといい
Look in the mirror.
そろいもそろって
典型的なダメ人間
Each and every one of you are exactly what people think of
when they talk about the scum of society.
クズでございってツラが
映るからよう
And you just accept it!
一生 浮かび上がれねえ顔だ
You'll never climb out of this pit.
いきなり なんだ てめえ？
カイジさん！
What the fuck's your problem?
Kaiji!?
俺もだ　俺も同じ
I know because I'm the same.
I'm the same way.
気がつきゃ 人生の隅っこ
I've realized that the dim corners of life...
世間の片隅
The back alleys of society...
そこが指定席
Are our places.
認められず 軽んじられ 疎まれ
Rejected, despised, shunned...
Unable to endure it, we fall further and further.
それに耐えられず 落下に次ぐ落下
学校でも社会でも
落ち続ける落下人生
In school, in society... Fall after fall.
こんな地の底まで落ちて…
All the way into this abyss.
なのに なんだ！
ここでも また負け組か
And what!? Are we still going to be losers here!?
この地の果てで
また負けるんかい！
Have we come all the way here to fail again!?
仲間かと思った班長にも
食い物にされてよ
Even the foreman acts friendly in order to use us.
気がつきゃ給料の半分をピンハネ
Before we even noticed, he was taking half our salary.
なんだ これ？
マヌケもいいとこだぜ
Guess there is a use for idiots.
その上 みんなも
聞いたことあるだろうが
Oh, and I'm sure you already know this...
班長たちは
ビールやつまみを売って
But the foreman and his gang split the beer and snacks money with Teiai.
その利益を
帝愛と折半してるらしい
そいつに俺たちから
ピンハネした金額を合わせると
Add that up with the interest he's charging us,
班長の懐に
一体いくら入ると思う？
and just how much money do you think he socks away?
ざっと計算して 72万だ
If I had to guess, I'd say around 720,000.
な… 70…
Seven hundred!?
何これ？コツコツ毎月９万ずつ
半年以上ためるなんて
What?
You think you can just save up half a million at 90 thou a month? That's retarded!
バカ丸出しじゃねえか
大槻なら きっと
こう言うだろうぜ
Think what Ohtsuki would be saying!
正気の沙汰じゃねえな
Now that's silly, isn't it?
大槻たちが潤い続け
俺たちがそれを支える
Ohtsuki and his gang get fat off our backs!
それでいいのかよ
Are you okay with that!?
仕方ねえだろ
We're damned either way.
It doesn't matter what you say, we can't do anything about it.
今さら そんなこと言ったって
どうにもなりゃしねえ
そうですよ カイジさん
仕方ないじゃないですか
Yeah, Kaiji! We're stuck!
いいのか？
このまま負け組のままで
Do you just want to keep being losers?
僕は負け組じゃない！
I'm not a loser!
いや 負け組だ
Yeah you are.
違う 違う 違う　聞きたくない！
No, no, no!
I don't want to hear it!
みんな こんな奴 相手にするな
Ignore him.
行こうぜ… あ？
Let's get out of here.
示す
何？
I'll show you.
Huh?
俺が勝ちへの道を示す
道？
I'll show you how to win!
How to win?
班長を… 大槻を倒し 大金を得る
We can take down Ohtsuki, and then we'll be rich.
勝つんだ　俺たちが！
We can win!
勝つって…
どうやって？
Win? You mean...
How?
どうやって大金を？
How do we win big?
一度だけ奇跡を見せる
I'll show you a miracle.
奇跡？
A miracle?
大槻には
ちょっとしたクセがあるのさ
Ohtsuki has this one little habit.
場が沸騰して
まさに今ここぞって時に
Right when the action gets hot--like right now--he has a habit of rolling well.
勝負強くなるクセがな
勝負だ！
俺も！
I'll take that bet!
Me too!
俺もだ！
And me!
頃合いだ
Just now...
いいか　一度だけだ
Just once...
ここ一度だけ
班長の目を言い当てる
Just this time, I'll guess the foreman's roll.
え？
そんなこと できるわけ…
That's impossible!
よーしと…
Here I go.
目はシゴロだ
It's gonna be 4-5-6.
うっ…
なんじゃ これ！
What!?
悪いな 皆の衆
Sorry, gentlemen.
シゴロだ
It's 4-5-6!
当たった…
当たった
You nailed it!
You were right...
倍づけだ　怖いのう 博打は
Looks like you're paying double.
Gambling really is fearsome.
ってことは イカサマか！野郎…
He's cheating!
That son of a bitch!
待て！どうするつもりだ？
決まってる！
Wait!
What are you gonna do?
Isn't it obvious? I'm gonna beat his ass until he owns up!
あいつをぶん殴ってでも
イカサマを白状させて…
それじゃダメだ　そんなことで
済ましちゃダメなんだ！
No! That won't solve anything!
だったら…
だったら どうする気だ
Then what? What do we do!?
いいから座れ
Sit back down!
確かに奴の強運には
偶然じゃない理由がある
Yeah, his rolls aren't just luck.
だが それと同時に
致命的な傷もある
But there's one fatal flaw.
そこを突く
ただしチャンスは一度きりだ
That's how we'll get him.
But we only have one chance.
本当に一回こっきりだが
One single shot.
奇襲で突き崩すことができる
We have to surprise him!
散々 利用され続けてきた俺たちが
We've been used! Hoodwinked! Bamboozled!
手にする千載一遇
最初で最後のチャンス
This is our once-in-a-lifetime chance!
今ここで立たなかったら
If we don't stand up now...
俺たちは生涯 奴隷だ！
We'll be slaves for the rest of our lives!
３万　俺の手持ち全額だ
I've got 30 thou.
出してくれ
みんなも手持ちの金 全部
Cough it up. Give me all your money.
手持ち全部？
All our money?
そうだ　どうせ
スッカラカン同然なんだろ
Yeah. We're all almost broke anyway.
Hurry it up!
早く
これだけだ　おい
This is all I have.
Here.
だ… 出しますよ
What do I do?
集まった金は 負け組
４５組６人のなけなしの金
The losers, the 45s, gather what few pennies they have!
わずかばかりの命の綱
The few threads holding them to life!
５… ６… ７
Five, six, seven...
合計で６万2700
All together, we've got 62,700.
これから３ヵ月 この金でしのぐ
We endure for the next three months on this.
しのぐ？
そうだ
Endure?
Yeah. We hold back on our meals.
飲み食いは制限　酒は禁止
No drinking. One smoke a day.
タバコは１日１本
博打はもってのほかだ
And absolutely no gambling.
ギリギリ切り詰めて 借金を返す
We live on the very edge, and pay off our loans.
晴れて正規の給料９万を
受け取れるようになったら
And once we start getting our 90 thou again...
その金で
We take that money...
大槻を殺る！
And we take down Ohtsuki.
小銭じゃ奴は殺せない
We need a bigger stack to finish him off.
せいぜいビックリさせて終わりだ
If he notices what's up, we're finished.
ダメなんだ そんなんじゃ
マックスでぶつかるんだ！
We can't let that happen.
We need to take him down in one shot!
今 俺たちがなし得る
最高マックス！
Let's have one hell of a shot ready!
さあ もういい加減
勝とうじゃないか！
All right, let's win this one!
重ねろ　この最初で最後の奇襲
Give me your hands!
Everyone who's ready to stake everything on this surprise attack...
最終戦略に乗る者は
俺の手に 手を！
Give me your hands!
Um... By 'winning big', you mean...
あの 大金ってことは つまり…
外へ行ける金額ってこと？
You mean getting enough money to get out of here?
当然だ
Of course.
そ… そうか
I see...
外へ… 外へ行けるなら…
If... If this gets us out of here...
I'm in!
乗った！
他は？
How about the rest of you?
ああ… お 俺…
I... I only put in 1,300, but...
1300しか出してねえんだけど
いいのか？
Am I okay?
そんなこと関係ねえ
It doesn't matter how much you put in.
あの ワシ…
今年42になるんだけど
I... I'm turning 42 this year...
関係ねえ
That doesn't matter.
そ… それじゃ乗った
乗った！
Then I'm in!
Me too!
お… 俺も乗せてくれ
Let me in too!
あと１人　どうする？
One left. Are you in or out?
どうもこうもねえ
There's no point in asking.
俺は ぐうたらだ
I'm worthless.
ぐうたらで その日暮らし
I don't do a damn thing with my life.
ダラダラ グズグズ生きてきた
でも本当は ずっと待ってた
But really I've always been waiting for this!
こんな日を
なんとか立ち上がるきっかけを
I was never able to stand up for myself alone, but now...
一人じゃ どうしても
できなかったが 今度は…
一緒に立ち上がりましょう
前田さん！
We stand together!
Maeda!
立ち上がって 勝つんだ！
We stand, and we win!
４５組 結束！
The 45s unite!
負け犬集団の中の負け組
Losers among losers, men trapped at the bottom of the abyss,
どん底の どん底男たちが
今 その手を重ね 立ち上がる
they join hands and stand!
To overthrow Ohtsuki!
打倒 大槻！
Proverbs of Kaiji Returns!
You're hopeless.
You don't have the nerves of steel a gambler needs. You just get carried away.
You love it when you finally win, but then the tables turn.
You're the kind of guy who's guaranteed to be a failure at life.